《终结者：救世军》
（朗维尤州立监狱 2003年）
马库斯
Marcus.
你怎么样
How are you?
一小时后再问吧
Ask me in an hour.
我想… 最后再和你谈一次
I thought I'd try… one last time.
你该呆在旧金山的 科根博士
You should have stayed in San Francisco, Dr. Kogan.
签下这份承诺书
By signing this consent form…
你的遗体会捐献给一项崇高的事业
you'd be donating your body to a noble cause.
你可以…
You'd…
得到救赎的机会
have a second chance,
我的研究可以让你重生
through my research, to live again.
你知道我的罪行
You know what I did.
我哥哥和两个警察 都是让我害死的
My brother and two cops are dead because of me.
我罪无可恕 不用给我救赎的机会
I'm not looking for a second chance.
而且 快死的不止我一个吧
But I'm not the only one with a death sentence, am I?
你觉得我能治好你的癌症吗
Do you think I'm gonna cure your cancer, Serena?
我考虑的不是自己
I'm not worried about myself.
而是人类的未来
I'm worried about the future of the human race.
好 卖给你了
I'll sell it to you.
什么条件
For what?
一个吻
A kiss.
这就是死亡的滋味
So that's what death tastes like.
（赛博坦公司 遗体捐献协议）
你参与了一项崇高的事业
You're doing something very noble.
不 我罪大恶极
No, I'm guilty.
赶紧把我碎尸万段吧
Just cut me up until there's nothing left.
「我虽然行过死荫的幽谷」
Yea, though I walk through the valley of the Shadow of Death,
「也不怕遭害 因为你与我同在」
I will fear no evil, for thou art with me.
「你的杖 你的竿 都安慰我」（圣经原文）
Thy rod and thy staff, they comfort me.
最后还有什么要说的吗
Do you have any last words?
21世纪初
天网 一种军事防务程序 自我觉醒
它将人类视作威胁 决定先发制人
核攻击的幸存者 称这一事件为「审判日」
幸存者面临着新的噩梦 一场与机器的战争
为了消灭人类 天网制造了终结者
随着战火蔓延 抵抗军领袖们愈发绝望
有人认为 有一个人可以拯救人类
也有人认为 他不过是虚假的先知
他叫约翰·康纳
这一年是 2018年
接近目标 天网研发基地
先锋 我是海盗旗六号
Vanguard, this is Blackjack 6.
导弹飞向天网目标
Missile inbound to Skynet target.
11秒后击中目标 危险迫近
TTO 11 seconds. Danger close.
康纳到达地面
Connor is on the ground.
这项任务 动作必须麻利
This mission is a quick in-and-out.
指挥部发话 搞到计算机里的情报
Command deems the information on those computers
是我们的首要任务
to be of the highest priority.
康纳 没发现敌人
Connor, there's no sign of the machines.
它们都走了
They're gone.
这儿太静了
It's way too quiet.
好像有埋伏似的
It's almost like they're waiting for us.
干掉了 干掉了
It's down, it's down.
这是什么鬼味道
What the hell's that smell, man?
看到这个没
You seeing this?
奥尔森 发现目标
Olsen. Objective located.
但有些我们意料之外的情况
There's something else you have to see.
干正事儿 巴尔巴罗萨
Get what we came for, Barbarosa.
没时间了
The clock's ticking.
散开 守住各个豁口
Spread out, secure the perimeter.
这儿一个大口子没人管
I got a big gap over here.
我们怎么对此一无所知？
Why didn't we know about this?
（登录破解 天网终端）
这大概就是指挥部要的东西
Sir, I think this is what Command's looking for.
我破译了源代码
I'm in their source code.
这些人要被运往旧金山
These people are being taken up north to San Francisco.
会被用于新型终结者的研发
Some sort of R&D project for a new Terminator.
发给指挥部
Send it to Command.
正在上传 需要2分钟
It's uploading. I need two minutes.
等等 后退 后退
Wait, wait, wait. Go back. Go back.
停
Stop.
（T-800之101型终结者）
- T-800 - 新型终结者
- T-800. - A new Terminator.
跟你说的一样
It's like you said it would be.
更糟
It's worse.
康纳 别管那个了
Connor, get your nose out of that.
不关你的事 你不是这次任务的指挥
None of your business. You're not leading this mission.
好了 放了这群可怜虫
Alright, let's cut these sorry bastards loose.
快 咱们撤
Come on. Let's go.
- 赫里科 回话 - 看那个
- Jericho, come in. - Watch that.
快回话 赫里科
Come in, Jericho.
康纳 你回地面去
Connor, get your ass topside.
告诉他们快回话
Remind those men they need to answer me on the radio,
死了也得吱声
even if they're dead.
康纳
Connor!
康纳 让他们回话
Connor, get those men to respond.
奥尔森 上面出事了
Olsen, something's wrong up here.
地面 回话
Topside, come in.
敌人的飞机飞走了 我去追
Outbound enemy aircraft. I'm in pursuit.
飞机上有人类囚犯 快去追
There're human prisoners aboard that thing. Get after it!
数据传输完毕
Data transfer complete.
康纳 我们去上面找…
Connor, we're joining you topsi…
B10 收到请回话 完毕
Bravo 10, Bravo 10, do you copy? Over.
E1呼叫B10 收到请回话 完毕
Eagle 1 to Bravo 10. Bravo 10, do you copy? Over.
B10 收到请回话 完毕
Bravo 10, Bravo 10, do you copy? Over?
收到
Here.
请表明身份 完毕
Bravo 10, identify. Over.
康纳
Connor.
我们将派人赶赴撤离点
We'll send units to the extraction point.
有多少幸存者 完毕
How many survivors are on-site? Over.
一个
One.
明白
Copy.
回基地吗 长官
Return to base, sir?
- 回基地吗 - 不
- RTB? - Negative.
- 带我去指挥部 - 长官
- Take me to Command. - Sir?
去指挥部
Command.
明白 改变航向
Roger. Rerouting.
请求被驳回
Request has been denied.
指挥部不想透露位置
Command doesn't wanna give up their position.
只接受无线电联络
Radio comms only.
- 他们在下面不？- 请求被驳回了 长官
- Are they down there? - Request has been denied, sir.
只披露必要信息 这是最高层的命令
Need-to-know only. That's straight from the top.
打开舱门
You open up that ramp…
派潜水员带我进舱 快
And you tell them I need divers for a log-in! Now!
真是疯了
This is crazy.
（抵抗军指挥部）
约翰·康纳
John Connor.
预言中的抵抗军领袖
Prophesized leader of the Resistance.
你的跳水表演
Soldier, you put every man and woman in this sub in jeopardy
给舱内的所有人带来了危险
with your little frogman stunt.
咱先说清楚
Let's get one thing straight.
我不信什么预言
I don't believe in prophecy.
特别是 我一秒钟就可以改写未来
Not when one can rewrite the future in a heartbeat.
你同意我说的吗？
Are we on the same page?
对 我同意
Yeah, we're on the same page.
很好 很好
Good. Good.
那么…
So, soldier…
你到底要干嘛
What the hell are you doing here?
我们在那儿找到了什么情报
What did we find down there?
有必要告诉你的才会告诉你
You'll be briefed on a need-to-know basis.
有必要告诉我
Well, I need to know,
因为我的人都死在那儿了
because my men died down in that hole.
告诉我 找到了什么
What did we find down there?
找到解决问题的办法了
We found a solution, Connor,
能彻底结束战争的办法
that can end this war once and for all.
咱都知道 机器用短波发射器联络
We know the machines use shortwave transmitters to communicate.
我们的情报员
Our intel has located
发现了一个隐藏在主频道下的信号
a hidden signal under the primary channel.
这种信号 可以直接控制那些机器
It allows for direct control over the machines.
天网也是机器 和其它机器一样
Skynet's a machine, and like all machines…
它也有关机键
it has an off-switch.
能管用吗
Does it work?
当然 但还没有实战测试过
Will it work? Yes. Have we field-tested it? No.
给我吧
Give it to me.
我来
I'll do it.
我去做实战测试
I'll test it.
康纳和他的技术通信小组 这方面很拿手
Connor and his tech-comm unit have an excellent record.
好吧
All right.
带康纳上去 准备出舱
Take Connor topside. Prepare for log-out.
这件事做成 战争就结束了
Connor, we do this right… The war is over.
4天后我们开始进攻
We mount our offensive in four days.
康纳
Connor.
这是信号的代码
These are the codes for the signal.
- 祝你好运 - 为什么是4天
- Good luck. - Why four days?
我们从天网截获了一份清除名单
A kill list was intercepted from Skynet.
按那名单 咱几个这周末都得死
It says everyone in this room will be dead by week's end.
你在名单上排第二
You're number two on the list.
那谁排第一
Well, who's number one?
无名之辈 一个平民
An unknown. A civilian.
卡友·里斯
Kyle Reese.
赫里科 回话
Jericho, come in.
快回话 赫里科
Come in, Jericho.
巴恩斯
Barnes.
我弟弟 他没回来？
My brother, he didn't make it, did he?
这是莎拉·康纳 给我儿子约翰的第28盘录音带
This is tape No. 28 of Sarah Connor to my son, John.
我最难决定的
What's most difficult is trying to decide
就是什么该告诉你 什么不该告诉你
what to tell you and what not to.
我该谈你父亲的事情吗
Should I tell you about your father?
如果知道他是你父亲
Will it affect your decision to send him back in time
你还会派他穿越时空 回到1984年来保护我吗
to protect me knowing that he is your father?
而且你遇到他时 他比你还小 才十几岁
And he'll be younger than you, only a teenager, when you meet him.
天啊 想到这些真让人发疯
God, a person could go crazy thinking about this.
但如果你不派卡友回来 你就不会存在
But if you don't send Kyle, you can never be
天网便会获胜
and Skynet will win the war.
想聊聊他吗
You want to talk about him?
（天网传输 关闭）
卡友孤身一人躲在外面 天网在找他
Kyle is out there somewhere alone, and Skynet is hunting him.
信号怎么样
What about the signal?
你来看看
What do you think?
（天网传输 关闭）
- 如果成功 那就太棒了 - 是啊
- If it works, it's incredible. - Yeah.
- 我们得小心点 - 对
- We have to be careful. - I agree.
- 但必须一试 - 好
- But we have to try. - Okay.
那么从小的熟悉的东西 开始试验吧
Alright, then start with something small that we're familiar with.
抓个机器水栖吧 拿它试试
We should capture a Hydrobot, bring it in for testing.
嗯
Yeah.
怎么了 约翰
What is it, John?
杀了卡友 就能改变未来
Kill Kyle Reese, reset the future…
就没有我的存在了
No John Connor.
（红小丑玩具公司）
想活命就跟我来
Come with me if you want to live.
那是什么玩意
What is that?
她不会说话 但你得开口
She doesn't talk, but you need to start.
外套从哪儿搞到的
Where did you get that jacket?
有个家伙不需要了
The other guy didn't need it.
看到这红色没
You see that red?
这代表鲜血 是抵抗军的标志
It stands for blood. It's a symbol of the Resistance.
但你显然不是抵抗军 所以给我脱下来
You're obviously not a Resistance fighter, so take it off.
脱下来
Take it off!
拿枪对着人
You point a gun at someone,
你得随时准备扣扳机
you'd better be ready to pull the trigger.
再问你一次
Now, I'm gonna ask you one more time.
- 那到底是什么玩意 - 终结者
- What the hell was that thing? - Terminator.
T-600型
T-600.
今天是几号
What day is it?
哪一年
What year?
2018年
2018.
发生什么事了
What happened here?
审判日发生了
Judgment Day happened.
我得离开这儿
I gotta get out of here.
走路可不行 机器会打死你
You can't go on foot. The machines will cut you down.
你得快
You need speed.
我要找辆车
I need a car.
格里菲思天文台附近有车
Well, look, there's some by Griffith Observatory.
- 但开不动了 - 带我去
- They don't run though. - Take me.
卧倒
Get down!
是猎杀者
That was a Hunter-Killer.
是你把它们引来的
Thanks to you, they know we're here.
你叫什么 小鬼
What's your name, kid?
卡友·里斯
Kyle Reese.
走吧
Come on.
烧掉了它的发射器 它没法和同伙通话了
We burned out his transmitter so it can't talk to any of its pals.
但还能接收
But he can still receive.
把信号打开
Turn it on.
摁住了？
You got it?
摁住 摁住
Hold it down, hold it down.
把信号开大
Turn the signal up.
把带子给我
Give me the strap.
- 我靠 - 奇迹啊
- Holy shit. - Can't you believe it?
好了 绑紧
All right. Strap it tight.
信号必须连贯
The signal has to be continuous.
如果有中断…
If there's any interruption…
（连接天网 搜索）
赶做一个便携短波发射器
Let's rig up a portable shortwave,
我要去实战测试更大的机器
I need to test it on something larger in the field.
好的
All right.
毁了它
Destroy this thing.
车在哪儿
So where are the cars?
天黑了可别出去
You don't wanna go out after dark.
猎杀者有红外眼 夜里看得更清楚
Hunter-Killers have infrared, hunt better at night.
咱明早再出去
We'll all go tomorrow morning.
- 这是什么 - 两天大的狼崽
- What is that? - Two-day-old coyote.
比三天大的好吃
Better than three-day-old coyote.
- 夺枪 - 什么
- Grab it. - What?
夺枪
Grab it.
魔术
Magic.
- 学会了？- 嗯
- Got it? - Yeah.
谢谢
Thanks.
收音机能用吗
Does this radio work?
坏了
No.
我爸试着修过 但一直没修好
My dad tried to fix it, but he could never get it to work.
拿着
Hold that.
人都哪儿去了
Where is everybody?
都走了
They're gone.
那你们怎么没走
So why are you still here?
因为我们是抵抗军 洛杉矶分部
Because we're the Resistance, L.A. branch.
欢迎来到司令部
Welcome to the headquarters.
抵抗什么
Resisting what?
机器 天网
Machines. Skynet.
- 就你俩？- 对
- Just the two of you? - Yeah.
那你怎么没有抵抗军标志
How come you're not wearing one of these?
我还没有赢得这个资格
'Cause I haven't earned mine yet.
希望他能听到
I hope he's listening to this.
经过长时间的艰苦战斗
We've been fighting a long time,
我们都付出了很大代价 失去了很多亲人
and we have all lost so very much, so many loved ones gone.
但你并不孤单
But you are not alone.
世界各地都有抵抗军
There are pockets of Resistance all around the planet.
现在是存亡攸关的时刻
We are at the brink.
想看魔术吗 拿着那个
Do you wanna see a magic trick? Hold that up.
摁下按钮
Press the button.
它们主武器的有效射程不足100米
Effective range of their main weapon is less than 100 meters.
它们携带大量弹药 但T-600笨重缓慢
They pack a lot of firepower, but the T-600s are heavy and slow.
是初级产品
They are a primitive design.
这是谁
Who is that?
如果被迫与它们近身
If you can't outrun them,
- 不知道 - 我教你一种办法
- I don't know. - then you have one option.
它们的运动皮质 有一部分暴露在后颈
Their motor cortex is partially exposed at the back of their neck.
用刀扎进去 会使其追踪装置失灵
A knife to this area will disorient their tracking device,
但时间不会长
but not for long.
最重要的 是活下来
Above all, stay alive.
你不知道自己有多重要
You have no idea how important you are
将来会有多重要
and how important you will become.
机器的升级速度 比我以前说过的还要快
The machines are advancing even faster than I told you they would.
我是亲眼所见
I've seen it with my own eyes.
它们在研制新的终结者 新的杀人武器
They're inventing new Terminators, new ways of killing us.
天网酝酿着重大举措
Skynet is planning something big.
但抵抗军会有更大的举措
But the Resistance is planning something bigger.
我是约翰·康纳
This is John Connor.
如果你在听 你就是抵抗军
If you're listening to this, you are the Resistance.
约翰·康纳
John Connor.
我们得找到他
We gotta find this guy.
修好了？
So… you get it working?
- 快了 - 好
- Almost. - Good.
咱是向东去 对吧
Look, I figure we head east, right?
穿过沙漠
We go through the desert,
就能与抵抗军会合了
then we can connect with the Resistance there.
- 我要去北边 - 不不不
- I'm heading north. - No, no, no.
整个北部地区 直到旧金山 都被机器控制了
The machines control the whole northern sector, up to San Francisco.
- 天网中心在那儿 - 我得去找个人
- That's Skynet Central. - I have to find someone.
拜托 你对天网了解太少了
There's a lot you don't understand about Skynet, okay?
去那边太危险了
It's just too dangerous for us to go there.
你们不是洛杉矶分部嘛
What about the L.A. branch?
好了 咱们真的必须离开洛杉矶
Come on, man. We need to get out of L.A.
什么歌
What is that?
我哥哥以前总听的
Something my brother used to listen to.
星星 下来
Star, get out.
别这么看着我
Don't look at me like that, Star.
下来 下来
Get out. Get out!
你要走？你要丢下我们？
You're leaving? You're gonna leave us?
好啊 明白了
Ah, I get it.
知道我们和机器的区别吗
You wanna know the difference between us and the machines?
我们埋葬死去的同伴
We bury our dead.
但没人会去埋你
But no one is coming to bury you.
间谍机
Aerostat!
- 终结者的侦察机 - 快走
- It's a scout for the Terminators. - Go, drive!
被间谍机听到音乐了
The Aerostats heard the music!
- 开稳点 - 我从没开过车
- Keep it steady! - I've never driven before.
你来握住方向盘
Hold the wheel!
（身份确认 卡友·里斯）
这玩意真烦人
This thing's pissing me off!
（卡友·里斯 资料上传）
小孩儿
Kid!
抓牢
Hold on!
如果咱想活下去 我来开车
If the idea is to stay alive, I'm driving.
敌人在洛杉矶动作很大
We're seeing a lot of enemy movement in L.A.
那儿有我们的人吗
Any of our people in the area?
没有地面部队 空中有两架A-10
No one on the ground. Two A-10s in the air.
威廉姆斯和默尔哈迪
Williams and Mihradi.
让战机过去
Send the birds in.
把那儿的人带到安全区域
Guide them to a safe area.
收到 郊狼67明白
Roger, Coyote 67 copies all.
正在飞向坐标LA1257903 完毕
Inbound to grid Lima-Alpha 1257903. Over.
- 收到 - 野鹰收到 完全明白
- Copy that. - Roger, Wild Eagle. Solid copy.
看来这儿有人啊
Hey, there's someone here.
趴下 趴下
Get down, get down! Get down. Down!
放下武器 举起手来
Drop your weapon! Let me see your hands!
不许动 放下武器 放下武器
Don't move. That's it, drop it. Put it down!
怎么回事
What?
- 怎么了 - 我们看到了你们的抵抗军标志
- Is there a problem? - Hey, we saw your Resistance sign.
是老太婆摆上的 不是我
The old lady put it there, not me.
- 你们来干嘛 - 我们需要燃料
- What do you want? - We're looking for fuel.
暗季要到了
The dark season's coming.
我们只够自己用的
We only got enough for ourselves.
拿枪对着人 你得随时准备扣扳机
You point that gun at somebody, you'd better be ready to pull the trigger.
都把枪给我放下
Put your guns down, everyone.
我们是来找抵抗军的 仅此而已
Look, we just came to find the Resistance, that's all.
抵抗军？
The Resistance?
笑话 跟那些机器根本没得打
What a joke. Fighting those machines is impossible.
我们老老实实的 他们就不理我们
We keep our heads down, they ignore us.
错了 它们最终还是会来抓你们
You keep your heads down and they'll come for you eventually.
我们要是帮你们 才会被抓
We help you, maybe they will.
这些人不会帮咱们 走吧
These people aren't going to help you. Let's go.
不要走
You're not going anywhere.
先让这孩子吃点东西
Not until this one gets something to eat.
拿一篮子来
Bring me a basket.
来吧
Here you go.
尽管吃 都吃光
Come on. Help yourself. Eat up.
你没事吧 孩子
Are you all right, son?
这是我们的食物
It's our food.
我们的燃料
Our fuel.
你不能做这个主
It's not your choice to make!
- 你没事吧 - 什么
- Are you okay? - What?
你没事吧
Are you okay?!
星星 星星
Star. Star. Star! Star!
你们 是你们把它们引来的
You! You brought them here! You brought them here!
- 停车 - 等等
- Stop, stop! - Come on, wait.
开车 别理他们
Go! Go! Forget them! Go! Go!
快
Go!
快去隧道那边
Tunnels! Head for the tunnels!
卡车
Truck!
马库斯 马库斯
Marcus. Marcus.
就这么跑 跑不掉的
We can't just run for it!
快跑
Run!
开枪
Shoot it!
快快快
Go, go, go!
不管用
It didn't work!
妈的
Shit!
太棒了
Hell, yeah!
摩托终结者
Moto-Terminators!
打它个狗杂种
Shoot that son of a bitch!
（躲避障碍物 主路线遇阻 刹车 分析替代路线）
马库斯 向右拐
Marcus, turn right up here.
坐稳
Hold on!
另一个跑哪儿去了
Where's the other one?
快回来
Get up here!
快
Come on.
星星 把枪给我
Star, give me the gun.
好了
I got it.
坐稳
Hang on!
- 把铁球放下去 - 好
- Drop the ball! - All right.
星星 抓牢
Star, hold on!
- 星星 星星 - 不
- Star! Star! - No!
- 卡友 - 马库斯
- Kyle! - Marcus.
退后
Get back.
马库斯 马库斯
Marcus! Marcus!
发现两架敌机
Got eyes on two targets.
270度方位发现两架敌机
We've got two bogeys at 270 degrees.
它们从未进到这么深 肯定是在找什么
They've never come this deep before. They're looking for something.
击落猎杀者
H.K. is down.
六点钟方向有猎杀者追击
We've got an H.K. pushing our six.
- 准备撤 - 正在努力摆脱
- Abort run. - Breaking off.
规避动作 快
Evasive maneuvers, now!
我被击中 左翼受损
Taking fire. I'm hit. Port-side damage.
它锁定你了 快摆脱
It's got a lock on you. Break off.
- 跳伞 威廉姆斯 - 启动弹射
- Eject, Williams, eject! - Punching out.
囚犯运输机向西北飞去了
Prisoner transport, headed northwest,
方位289 旧金山方向
bearing 2-8-9 towards San Francisco.
测试下信号吧
Let's test the signal…
但愿管用
And pray it works.
你没事吧
You okay?
把我的刀给我 左脚靴子里
Get my knife. It's in my left boot.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
布莱尔·威廉姆斯
Blair Williams.
你呢
What's yours?
教名是马库斯
Name's Marcus.
你可以把我放下了 马库斯
You can let me down now, Marcus.
- 那玩意去哪儿了 - 那架运输机？
- That thing, where'd it go? - The transport?
天网
Skynet.
- 你要去哪儿 - 去追它
- Where the hell are you going? - After it.
不是我打击你
Hate to break it to you but…
如果你朋友在那运输机上
If you've got friends on that thing…
他们必死无疑
They're good as dead.
你要是去追它 你也活不成
The same with you if you keep walking in that direction.
我早就死了 习惯了
Yeah, well I've been dead a while and I'm getting used to it.
跟我回基地吧
Why don't you come with me to my base?
康纳也许有办法
Connor might know a way.
听着 如果你对机器有怨念
Listen, if you've got a problem with the machines,
跟他谈谈准没错
he's definitely the guy you wanna talk to.
- 基地离这儿多远？- 走路一两天吧
- How far is your base? - It should be 1 or 2 days hike.
是那个方向
And it's that way.
你要相信我 我们不会死的
我们不会死的
你们说什么呢 讲英语
What are you saying? Speak English!
我在告诉他 机器不会杀我们
I was telling him it is not true about the machines killing us.
错了 它们会把我们全杀光
They're gonna kill us. They're gonna kill everyone.
我们现在就是一群牲口 正被运往屠宰场
We are in a cattle cart, on our way to the slaughterhouse.
冷静点 这样没好处
Calm down. You're not helping.
现在最重要的 是活下来
The most important thing that we can do right now is stay alive.
用脑子 用心
In here and in here.
懂了吗 活下来
Alright? Just stay alive.
那边
Over there.
去找东西生火 明天就能到基地了
Find something we can burn. We'll be at my base tomorrow.
你受伤了吗
Are you hurt?
我没事
I'm fine.
你那是什么
What'd you got there?
一些抗生素
Just some antibiotics.
这年头抗生素很难找啊
Antibiotics are hard to come by these days.
我这儿不多 但你想要的话 都拿走
Listen. I don't have much, but you're welcome to whatever you need.
我们一直盯着你呐
We've been watching you.
找这个呐？
You looking for this?
拜托 伙计们 机器才是敌人
Come on, guys. The machines are the enemy.
- 我们是朋友 - 不不
- We're on the same side. - No, no.
我这儿有几个朋友了
You see, I've got a couple of friends on my side.
等我把你打趴下 他们可以背你回家呵
Maybe they can carry you home when I'm done with you.
您好像没上子弹
You might want to chamber a round.
抓到一个肥臀妞儿 等了很久啦
We done caught us a donkey! Been waiting for you.
里克特
Richter!
杀了我也打不赢战争
Killing me ain't gonna win this war!
在想你的过去？
Thinking about your past?
知道我明白了一个什么道理吗
You know what I've learned, Marcus?
要么 你为已逝的过去叹息
Is you can focus on what is lost…
要么 你为眼前的现实奋斗
…or you can fight for what is left.
我有点冷
I'm a little cold.
别紧张
Relax.
只是想要点体温
I just want some body heat.
你的心跳好有力
You have a strong heart.
我太喜欢这声音了
God, I love that sound.
谢谢你救了我
Thank you… for saving me back there.
这年头好人不多了
I don't meet a lot of good guys these days.
我不是个好人
I'm not a good guy.
你是
You are.
你只是还没意识到
You just don't know it yet.
你觉得 人应该得到救赎的机会吗
Do you think people deserve a second chance?
嗯 应该
Yeah. I do.
就这儿了 天网的死亡之谷
This is it. Skynet's valley of death.
咱从没进过这么深
We've never been this deep before.
得在它们的地盘 找个更大的机器…
We gotta be sure the signal works in their territory…
测试一下才行
on the bigger machines.
这会把它们引来
That'll bring them in.
猎杀者 来了
H.K. incoming.
开大
Turn it up!
成功了 信号管用 太棒了
It works, man. The signal works. It's beautiful.
接通了阿什当司令
Commander Ashdown's on.
康纳 成功没？
Connor, tell me it works.
成功了 信号确实管用
It works. That is affirmative. The signal works.
很好 明晨4点 在全球展开进攻
Good. The attack commences tomorrow at 0400, worldwide.
你的部队去协助轰炸天网中心
Your unit will be in support of the bombing of Skynet Central.
怎么营救那些囚犯
What is the extraction plan for the prisoners?
营救囚犯？根本没有营救计划
Extraction plan? There is no extraction plan.
我们只管把那儿炸平
We're gonna level the place.
不行 我说过了…
Negative. I told you…
天网中心关押着大批人类囚犯
Skynet Central is filled with human prisoners!
这是战争
This is war, Connor.
领袖应该懂得牺牲 你应该最清楚这点
Leadership has its costs. You, above all, should know that.
阿什当 回话
Ashdown, come in.
阿什当 我是康纳
Ashdown, Connor.
阿什当 回… 这孙子！
Ashdown, come… Damn him!
星星 退后 退后
Star! Get back! Get back!
你得赶快冷静下来
You have to calm down now.
我要离开这儿 我要离开这儿
I gotta get out! I gotta get out of here!
布莱尔
Blair.
怎么了
What?
这是我们的磁铁地雷
This is us. The mines are magnetic.
从这个入口直奔西走 就不会有事
If we head due west at this point of entry, we're good.
我先走
I'll go first.
快点 马库斯 我都饿死了
Let's go, Marcus. I'm starving.
「因为你与我同在」
For thou art with me.
「你的杖 你的竿 都安慰我」
Thy rod and thy staff, they comfort me.
神父
Father.
这是美好未来的开始
This is the beginning of something wonderful.
这混蛋真沉
Son of a bitch is heavy.
- 什么情况 - 他踩上地雷了
- What've we got here? - He stepped on a land mine.
大口径静脉注射
Start a large-bore IV.
- 保持开放 加大吗啡剂量 - 我挺得住
- Keep it open. More morphine. - I'm okay.
- 他叫什么 - 马库斯
- What's his name? - Marcus.
- 他有假肢？- 什么
- He's got a prosthetic limb? - What?
脉搏正常 看看都伤哪儿了
Okay, pulse is good. Let's see what we've got.
巴恩斯
Barnes.
它们技术进步真快啊
The devil's hands have been busy.
这是什么东西
What is it?
血肉都是人类的 但愈合速度很快
It's real flesh and blood, though it seems to heal itself quickly.
心脏是人类的 非常强健
The heart is human and very powerful.
脑子也是人类的 但有个芯片接口
The brain too, but with a chip interface.
- 你们把我怎么样了 - 它有一套混和神经系统
- What have you done to me? - It has a hybrid nervous system.
既有人类皮质 也有机器
One human cortex, one machine.
布莱尔 他们干了什么
Blair, what have they done?
谁制造的你
Who built you?
我叫马库斯·赖特
My name is Marcus Wright.
你认为自己是人类？
You think you're human?
我是人类
I am human.
不
No!
你是在哪儿生产的
Where were you manufactured?
我出生于…
I was born…
1975年8月22号
August 22nd, 1975.
我知道你
I know you.
我在广播里听过你的讲话
I heard your voice on the radio.
- 你是约翰·康纳 - 你当然知道我
- You're John Connor. - Of course you know me.
你是被派来杀我的
You were sent here to kill me.
刺杀领袖
Kill the leadership.
- 听不懂你在说什么 - 那你来这儿干嘛
- I don't know what you're talking about. - Then why are you here?
布莱尔说 你能帮我找到一个人
Blair said you could help me find who I'm looking for.
把我放下来
Now let me down.
如果把你放下来
If I let you down…
你会把我们都干掉
you'll kill everyone in this room.
只杀你 康纳
Just you, Connor.
因为我实在不鸟你
'Cause I ain't give a shit about you.
我两天前才知道有你这么个人
I didn't even know your name until two days ago.
不对
No.
你和我…
You and me…
我们来到这个世界之前 就开始较量了
We've been at war since before either of us even existed.
你企图杀害我的母亲 莎拉·康纳
You tried killing my mother, Sarah Connor.
你杀了我的父亲 卡友·里斯
You killed my father, Kyle Reese.
但你杀不了我
You will not kill me.
卡友·里斯在运输机上 正被押送至天网
Kyle Reese is on a transporter, heading for Skynet.
如果我想杀他
If I wanted to kill him,
在洛杉矶就动手了
I would have done him in L.A.
在哪儿碰到那家伙的
Where did you find that thing?
你派我和默尔哈迪去护送百姓
You sent Mihradi and me to provide cover for some civilians.
他是其中之一
He was one of them.
那儿有一个十几岁孩子吗
Was there a teenage boy?
这个真不知道
I honestly don't know.
它们把百姓押上运输机 他是唯一一个逃脱的
They were taken into a transport. He was the only one left.
不是「他」 是「它」
Not "he, " Blair: "It."
「它」是唯一一个逃脱的 别傻了
It was the only one left. Don't be naive.
「它」救了我的命
It saved my life.
凯特 会怎么处置他
Kate, what's gonna happen to him?
肢解
Disassembled.
就是说要杀了他
You mean killed.
从它身上 也许可以找到天网的情报
It may have information on Skynet.
他不是敌人
I know he's not the enemy.
是敌人向我开枪 不是他
I've been shot at by the enemy. That's not him.
那机器救你 是为了混进来把我们都干掉
That machine saved you only to gain access to kill all of us.
（卡友·里斯 身份确认）
我们不会有事 别怕
We're gonna be okay. Don't worry.
为了我弟弟
For my brother.
不
No!
康纳要见你
Connor wants to see you.
什么事
What for?
你觉得他会告诉我吗
Like he's gonna tell me, Barnes.
让我试试
Let me see that.
要不我告诉康纳你不想去？
You want me to tell Connor you're not coming?
别
No.
看住他
Watch him.
我把知道的都告诉你了 约翰
I told you everything I know, John.
天网冷酷无情 诡计多端
Skynet is ruthless and unpredictable.
它们会令你以己之矛攻己之盾
They will use the best part of you against yourself,
它们还会有一些我无法想象的招数
and they will have methods I can't imagine or predict.
这些我真的帮不了你了
That I can't help you with.
当你陷入茫然
And when you're unsure,
跟随自己的心吧 约翰
well just always follow your heart, John.
我爱你 再见
I love you. Goodbye.
录音带里没提到带器官的机器
There's nothing on the tapes about machines with organs.
那个家伙…
That thing in there…
我以为我了解敌人
I thought I knew our enemy.
但那家伙 让我觉得自己一无所知
But that thing, that makes me feel like I know nothing.
我从它的眼神看出…
I looked in its eyes, and it believes,
它真的深信自己是人类
absolutely believes, that it is human.
它真的认为 自己每句话都是实话
It believes everything that it says,
它告诉我
And it is telling me…
卡友就在天网
that Kyle Reese is in Skynet.
如果真是这样…
If that is true…
指挥部将炸死我父亲
Then Command is about to bomb my father
以及其他囚犯
and the rest of those prisoners
而我却无能为力
and I cannot stop them.
谢谢
Thank you.
进来
Come in!
什么事 布莱尔说你叫我
What's up? Blair said you needed me.
进去
Get in.
干掉他们
Kill them.
巴恩斯 布莱尔也在下面呢
Barnes. What about Blair?
她咎由自取
She made her choice.
卧倒
Get down!
快走
Let's move.
探照灯 那里
Get some light out there!
又回地雷阵了
We're back in the minefield.
我计划好了
I have a plan.
- 快跑 - 他们正在逃跑
- Let's run! - There they go, they're on the move.
- 你没事吧 - 没事
- Blair, you okay? - Yeah, I'm okay!
- 看不到了 - 在那里
- I can't see back! - There they are!
快跑
Run! Go!
下一步计划？
Now what?
我的计划 就截止到那辆吉普
M-My plan stopped at the jeep.
狙击一组 打得到他们吗
Sniper Team 1, do you have a shot?
我吸引火力 你把灯打灭
I'll draw the fire. You take out the light.
发现目标
I got the target!
- 在墙后面 - 不许动
- Behind the wall. - Don't move. Do not move!
快跑 低头 低头
Go! Now! Keep your head down! Keep your head down!
- 快快快 - 快快快
- Go, go, go! - Go, go, go!
快 快跑
Go! Go, keep running!
挺住 挺住
Come on! Come on!
- 你没事吧 - 赶紧逃出这里
- You alright? - Let's get you out of here.
在那儿呢
There they are!
趴在地上 不许动
Stay on the ground! Stay on the ground!
赶快下来 我过来了
You come on straight down. I'm going in.
- 不许动 - 看住他们
- Do not move! - Keep your eye on them.
把他翻过来
Flip him!
铁鳄 我是疤面人51 发现机器行踪
Iron Gator, this is Scarface 51. We have eyes on the machine.
火力打击开始
Contact initiated.
你来架机枪
Take my gun!
查看水面
Check the river.
发现他了吗
You see him?
没液压了
Hydraulics are out!
弗尔
Fall.
把手给我 把手给我
Give me your hand! Give me your hand!
你不知道自己是什么 但大家都知道
They know what you are, even if you don't.
够了
Enough!
你那枪管个屁用
That gun ain't gonna stop shit.
要是打中你心脏呢
Nobody shot you in the heart,
你那就是普通的人类心脏
and I see that thing beating a mile a minute.
卡友·里斯
Kyle Reese…
他在天网 你杀了我 他也活不成了
He's in Skynet. You do that, he's dead.
我能带你进去
I can get you in.
怎么带
How?
看看我
Look at me.
所以我无法信任你
That's why I don't trust you.
但我是你唯一的希望
I'm the only hope you have.
我想知道是谁把我变成这样
I need to find who did this to me.
你也一样
So do you.
康纳
Connor!
你决定吧
Make your choice.
你带我进去
You get me in.
并且告诉我卡友·里斯在哪儿
You tell me where I can find Kyle Reese.
对吗
Yeah?
对
I will.
用这个联系我 让我知道他还活着
Contact me on that. Let me know he's still alive.
你到底是什么
What are you?
我不知道
I don't know.
他在这儿呢
Hey, he's over here.
你没事吧
You all right?
看到他了吗
Any sign of him?
他跑了
He's gone.
为什么那么做
Why did you do it?
我看到的 是一个活生生的人 不是机器
I saw a man… not a machine.
腿怎么样
How's that leg?
死不了
I'll live.
放了她
Let me go!
康纳 指挥部找你
Connor? Command for you.
- 我是康纳 - 你的部队准备好没有
- This is Connor. - Connor, are your men ready?
不 大家都没准备好
Negative. Nobody is ready.
我们没有 你们也没有
We are not, you are not.
必须放弃进攻计划 情况变了
We must abort the attack. The game has changed.
说什么呢你
What are you talking about?
部队都已经就位
All elements are past their release points.
已经进入攻击位置
They are in assault position.
那至少要推迟进攻 至少要推迟
Then delay the attack. At least, delay the attack.
我有机会潜入天网
I have a chance to infiltrate Skynet
营救那些囚犯
and rescue those prisoners.
给我这个机会
Give me that opportunity.
绝对不行 根本没有营救计划
No, absolutely not! This is not the time for a rescue mission!
你的要求 会破坏整个行动
What you ask for, will undermine the whole operation.
卡友·里斯关在天网
Skynet has Kyle Reese.
- 那是他的命运 - 不 他事关人类的命运
- Then that is his fate. - No, it's our fate.
我必须救他 他是关键
I have to save him. He is the key.
对未来和过去 都是关键
The key to the future, to the past.
没有他 我们会一败涂地
Without him, we lose everything.
不行 你给我按原计划执行
No! You stay the course!
如果按原计划执行 我们就死定了
If we stay the course, we are dead!
我们全都死定了
We are all dead!
现在我宣布
As of this moment, soldier,
解除你的指挥权
you are relieved of your command.
你被抵抗军开除了
You are no longer a part of this Resistance.
我没听懂他最后一句
I didn't catch that last statement.
我也没听懂
Neither did I.
我是约翰·康纳
This is John Connor.
如果你在听 你就是抵抗军
If you're listening to this, you are the Resistance.
仔细听好 如果今晚发起进攻
Listen carefully. If we attack tonight…
我们就失去了人性
our humanity is lost.
我曾认识一个女人 她告诫人们警惕未来
I once knew a woman who told people to fear the future…
她提醒人们 世界末日将至
that the end was coming, that all would be lost.
但没人相信她 她被关了起来
Nobody wanted to hear her truths. Society locked her away.
那个女人名叫莎拉·康纳 我的母亲
That woman was Sarah Connor, my mother.
现在我们都知道 她的预言全部成真
Now we know that what she predicted has all come to pass.
指挥部要我们像机器那样战斗
Command wants us to fight like machines.
要求我们冷血地 程式般地行动
They want us to make cold, calculated decisions.
但我们不是机器
But we are not machines.
如果我们沦为机器一般
And if we behave like them,
那么赢得战争 又有什么意义
then what is the point… in winning?
指挥部会要求你们发起进攻
Command is going to ask you to attack Skynet.
但我请求你们不要
I am asking you not to.
天亮前 哪怕有一颗炸弹落在天网中心
If even one bomb drops on Skynet before sunrise,
我们就失去了未来
our future will be lost.
我恳请大家停止行动 请给我时间
So please, stand down. Give me the time…
去捍卫我们为之战斗的未来
to protect our future, that all of us, are fighting for.
我是约翰·康纳
This is John Connor.
如果你的人发现你走了 我该怎么说
What should I tell your men when they find out you're gone?
我会回来
I'll be back.
（破解 回到出发点）
（天网控制区 北门）
（入口安检）
（分析 马库斯·赖特 工作状态 允许进入）
我来找你了
I'm coming for you.
快点 马库斯
Come on, Marcus.
（等待信号）
（马库斯·赖特 身份确认）
（等待资格认证）
（同步完成）
（北区炮塔关闭 武装解除）
（4a监室 卡友·里斯）
（传送方位）
好了
Okay.
（杀人犯向科学事业捐献遗体）
（科根博士因癌症去世）
（赛博坦公司继续致力于 科根博士未竟的自动化研究）
（美国空军收购赛博坦系统）
（天网启动）
（解锁）
信号正以最大功率播放 长官
Signal broadcasting at full strength, sir.
很好 开始轰炸天网中心
Good. Commence bombing of Skynet.
指挥部下令开始进攻
We have a green light for the attack.
我是贝克斯菲尔德 拒绝执行此项命令 完毕
This is Bakersfield. That's a no-go on your last. Out.
尤金停止行动
Eugene, standing down.
我是雷诺 拒绝此项命令
This is Reno. Negative on your last.
尤金 雷诺 贝克斯菲尔德 都拒绝执行
Eugene, Reno, Bakersfield. They're all standing down.
除非康纳下令 否则他们不会进攻
They will not attack unless Connor gives the order.
（牢门已锁）
（牢门解锁）
卡友·里斯
Kyle Reese?
快上运输机 卡友·里斯在吗
Get to the transport! Go! Is Kyle Reese here?
欢迎回家 马库斯
Welcome home. Marcus.
我们知道你会回来
We knew you'd be back.
毕竟 这是程序对你的指引
After all, it was programmed in you.
而且你对程序的执行 非常漂亮
Oh, and you executed that programming beautifully.
我是什么
What am I?
你是渗入型间谍机器人
You are an infiltration prototype,
是独一无二的
the only one of your kind.
我们使你复活
We resurrected you.
赛博坦公司的超前技术 使你更先进
Advanced Cyberdyne's work… amended it.
你已经死了
You're dead.
分析结果显示
Calculations confirmed
科根博士的脸 最便于你的处理
Serena Kogan's face is the easiest for you to process.
你乐意的话 还可显示其它面孔
We can be others if you wish.
马库斯
Marcus…
除了机器 你还能是什么呢
What else could you be… if not machine?
我是人类
A man.
你不再符合作为人类的条件了
The human condition no longer applies to you.
接受现实吧
Accept what you already know…
我们制造你 是为了一个目的
That you were made to serve a purpose.
去完成其它机器从未完成过的任务
To achieve what no another machine has achieved before.
渗入敌营 找到目标
To infiltrate, find a target,
然后把他带给我们
and then bring that target back home to us.
我们来到这个世界之前 就开始较量了
We've been at war since before either of us even existed.
你企图杀害我的母亲 莎拉·康纳
You tried killing my mother, Sarah Connor.
你带我进去
You get me in.
并且告诉我卡友·里斯在哪儿
You tell me where I can find Kyle Reese.
- 对吗 - 对
- Yeah? - I will.
卡友·里斯 卡友·里斯 快走 快走
Kyle Reese! Kyle Reese! Move! Move!
卡友·里斯
Kyle Reese!
快上运输机
Get to your transport.
卡友·里斯
Kyle Reese!
不
No!
你 快走
You, move!
当人类开始铤而走险
In times of desperation,
他们就会把理想误当成现实
people will believe what they want to believe.
于是 我们就把理想呈现给他们
And so, we gave them what they wanted to believe.
我们设计了那个信号的圈套
A trick, in the form of a signal,
抵抗军以为可以藉此结束战争
the Resistance thought would win the war.
他们没错 战争的确会结束
And they were right, it will end this war.
只不过 被终结的将是抵抗军
Except that it is the Resistance that will be terminated,
不是天网
not Skynet.
重新启动对天网中心的进攻
Get the attack on Skynet Central back online.
我命令空军立刻出动
I want our aircraft in the sky, immediately!
长官 雷达发现大型飞行物
Sir, sir, we got a bogey with a very large radar signature
正向我们逼近
closing in on our position.
洛森科将军
Losenko?
（船体被锁定）
我们玩了一场自我毁灭
We have destroyed ourselves.
天网跟踪了我们的信号
Skynet tracked our signal.
是我们自己把它们引来了
We led them straight to us.
我们最精尖的机器 也一次次失败
Our best machines have failed time and again to complete the mission.
我们工作不够周密 我们痛定思变
Something was missing. We had to think, radically.
所以 我们制造了你
And so we made you.
你是完美的渗入型间谍机器
We created the perfect infiltration machine.
马库斯
You, Marcus.
你完成了天网多年不曾完成的任务
You did what Skynet has failed to do for so many years.
你杀死了约翰·康纳
You killed John Connor.
卡友
Kyle!
不要反抗 马库斯
Don't fight, Marcus.
记住你的身份
Remember what you are.
我知道自己的身份
I know what I am.
还是这样好
I'm better this way.
我们不会给你救赎的机会
You will not be given a second chance.
你救不了约翰·康纳
You cannot save John Connor.
走着瞧
Watch me.
康纳传来讯息了
Got a message from Connor.
他在天网 需要空中支援
He's in Skynet. Needs air support.
行动 紧急起飞
Let's go! Scramble aircraft.
星星 快跑
Star! Star, go!
星星
Star!
星星 快走 快走
Star! Star! Come on. Come on.
（瞄准系统混乱）
- 你叫什么 - 卡友·里斯
- What's your name? - Kyle Reese.
跟我走
Stay with me.
退后
Back!
星星 快走
Come on, Star, move!
T-800
T-800s.
居然这么多
There's so many of them.
当心
Careful.
- 这是什么 - 燃料电池
- What are these? - Fuel cells.
T-800的能量源
Life source for the T-800.
核能的
Nuclear.
足够把这儿炸平
Enough to level this place.
掩护我们
Cover us.
准备好
Get ready.
来了
This is it.
快跑
Run!
星星 快走
Star, come on! Let's go!
进去
Get in.
- 快啊 - 快啊
- Come on! - Come on!
我们得赶到运输机那里
We gotta get to the transport.
- 你去哪儿 - 我得把这儿炸平
- Where are you going? - I gotta end this.
不行 我不能丢下你
No, no. I'm not gonna leave you!
- 你没有 - 你是谁
- You didn't. - Who are you?
约翰·康纳
John Connor!
（首要目标：约翰·康纳）
（人类心脏 脆弱部位）
（生命迹象：无 已被终结）
（跟踪：约翰·康纳）
（错误 位置：不明）
约翰·康纳在里面 他还在里面
Hey! Hey, John Connor's in there. He's still in there.
克里斯 她血容量低 给她输血
Chris, she's hypovolemic, start a line!
- 什么 - 约翰·康纳在里面
- What? - John Connor's in there.
跟我来
Come with me.
康纳
Connor!
康纳 救命
Connor, help!
救命
Help!
康纳 我是卡友 救命
Connor, it's Kyle! Help!
来吧 你个狗娘养的
Do it! You son of a bitch!
醒醒
Come on!
快醒醒
咱们走
Let's get out of here.
约翰…
John…
不能回基地了
We can't make it back to base.
在最近的安全区域降落吧
Set this down in the nearest safe zone.
救伤直升机 紧急情况 伤员胸口严重创伤
Medevac, urgent. Severe chest trauma.
联络手术小组 注意 是康纳
Call the surgical team. Remarks: it's Connor.
还能撑多久
How long?
他的心脏…
His heart…
不行了
can't take it.
不会有事的 不会有事的 凯特
It's gonna be okay. It's gonna be okay, Kate.
卡友
Kyle?
那是给你的
Take it…
你赢得的
You earned it.
凯特
Kate…
用我的
Take mine.
马库斯
Marcus?
人人都该有救赎的机会
Everybody deserves a second chance.
这是我的
This is mine.
是什么 让我们成为人
What is it that makes us human?
那不是一种程序
It's not something you can program.
无法写入芯片
You can't put it into a chip.
那是人类心灵的力量
It's the strength of the human heart.
是它 使我们区别于机器
The difference between us and machines.
暴风雨就要到来
There is a storm on the horizon.
那又将是一个艰苦的时期
A time of hardship and pain.
我们打赢了这场战斗
This battle has been won,
但与机器的战争 仍在激烈进行
but the war against the machines rages on.
天网的全球网络依然强大
Skynet's global network remains strong.
但我们不会放弃
But we will not quit…
直至将天网彻底摧毁
until all of it is destroyed.
我是约翰·康纳
This is John Connor.
没有命运 我们创造命运
There is no fate but what we make.
[谨以此片纪念斯坦·温斯顿]